
For Carl Solomon I I saw the best minds of my generation destroyed by madness, starving hysterical naked, dragging themselves through the negro streets at dawn looking for an angry fix, angelheaded hipsters burning for the ancient heavenly connection to the starry dynamo in the machinery of night, who poverty and tatters and hollow-eyed and high sat up smoking in the supernatural darkness of cold-water flats floating across the tops of cities contemplating jazz, who bared their brains to Heaven under the El and saw Mohammedan angels staggering on tenement roofs illuminated, who passed through universities with radiant cool eyes hallucinating Arkansas and Blake-light tragedy among the scholars of war, who were expelled from the academies for crazy & publishing obscene odes on the windows of the skull, who cowered in unshaven rooms in underwear, burning their money in wastebaskets and listening to the Terror through the wall, who got busted in their pubic beards returning through Laredo with a belt of marijuana for New York, who ate fire in paint hotels or drank turpentine in Paradise Alley, death, or purgatoried their torsos night after night with dreams, with drugs, with waking nightmares, alcohol and cock and endless balls, incomparable blind; streets of shuddering cloud and lightning in the mind leaping toward poles of Canada & Paterson, illuminating all the motionless world of Time between, Peyote solidities of halls, backyard green tree cemetery dawns, wine drunkenness over the rooftops, storefront boroughs of teahead joyride neon blinking traffic light, sun and moon and tree vibrations in the roaring winter dusks of Brooklyn, ashcan rantings and kind king light of mind, who chained themselves to subways for the endless ride from Battery to holy Bronx on benzedrine until the noise of wheels and children brought them down shuddering mouth-wracked and battered bleak of brain all drained of brilliance in the drear light of Zoo, who sank all night in submarine light of Bickford's floated out and sat through the stale beer after noon in desolate Fugazzi's, listening to the crack of doom on the hydrogen jukebox, who talked continuously seventy hours from park to pad to bar to Bellevue to museum to the Brooklyn Bridge, lost battalion of platonic conversationalists jumping down the stoops off fire escapes off windowsills off Empire State out of the moon, yacketayakking screaming vomiting whispering facts and memories and anecdotes and eyeball kicks and shocks of hospitals and jails and wars, whole intellects disgorged in total recall for seven days and nights with brilliant eyes, meat for the Synagogue cast on the pavement, who vanished into nowhere Zen New Jersey leaving a trail of ambiguous picture postcards of Atlantic City Hall, suffering Eastern sweats and Tangerian bone-grindings and migraines of China under junk-withdrawal in Newark's bleak furnished room, who wandered around and around at midnight in the railroad yard wondering where to go, and went, leaving no broken hearts, who lit cigarettes in boxcars boxcars boxcars racketing through snow toward lonesome farms in grandfather night, who studied Plotinus Poe St. John of the Cross telepathy and bop kabbalah because the cosmos instinctively vibrated at their feet in Kansas, who loned it through the streets of Idaho seeking visionary indian angels who were visionary indian angels, who thought they were only mad when Baltimore gleamed in supernatural ecstasy, who jumped in limousines with the Chinaman of Oklahoma on the impulse of winter midnight street light smalltown rain, who lounged hungry and lonesome through Houston seeking jazz or sex or soup, and followed the brilliant Spaniard to converse about America and Eternity, a hopeless task, and so took ship to Africa, who disappeared into the volcanoes of Mexico leaving behind nothing but the shadow of dungarees and the lava and ash of poetry scattered in fire place Chicago, who reappeared on the West Coast investigating the F.B.I. in beards and shorts with big pacifist eyes sexy in their dark skin passing out incomprehensible leaflets, who burned cigarette holes in their arms protesting the narcotic tobacco haze of Capitalism, who distributed Supercommunist pamphlets in Union Square weeping and undressing while the sirens of Los Alamos wailed them down, and wailed down Wall, and the Staten Island ferry also wailed, who broke down crying in white gymnasiums naked and trembling before the machinery of other skeletons, who bit detectives in the neck and shrieked with delight in policecars for committing no crime but their own wild cooking pederasty and intoxication, who howled on their knees in the subway and were dragged off the roof waving genitals and manuscripts, who let themselves be fucked in the ass by saintly motorcyclists, and screamed with joy, who blew and were blown by those human seraphim, the sailors, caresses of Atlantic and Caribbean love, who balled in the morning in the evenings in rose gardens and the grass of public parks and cemeteries scattering their semen freely to whomever come who may, who hiccuped endlessly trying to giggle but wound up with a sob behind a partition in a Turkish Bath when the blond & naked angel came to pierce them with a sword, who lost their loveboys to the three old shrews of fate the one eyed shrew of the heterosexual dollar the one eyed shrew that winks out of the womb and the one eyed shrew that does nothing but sit on her ass and snip the intellectual golden threads of the craftsman's loom, who copulated ecstatic and insatiate with a bottle of beer a sweetheart a package of cigarettes a candle and fell off the bed, and continued along the floor and down the hall and ended fainting on the wall with a vision of ultimate cunt and come eluding the last gyzym of consciousness, who sweetened the snatches of a million girls trembling in the sunset, and were red eyed in the morning but prepared to sweeten the snatch of the sun rise, flashing buttocks under barns and naked in the lake, who went out whoring through Colorado in myriad stolen night-cars, N.C., secret hero of these poems, cocksman and Adonis of Denver--joy to the memory of his innumerable lays of girls in empty lots & diner backyards, moviehouses' rickety rows, on mountaintops in caves or with gaunt waitresses in familiar roadside lonely petticoat upliftings & especially secret gas-station solipsisms of johns, & hometown alleys too, who faded out in vast sordid movies, were shifted in dreams, woke on a sudden Manhattan, and picked themselves up out of basements hung over with heartless Tokay and horrors of Third Avenue iron dreams & stumbled to unemployment offices, who walked all night with their shoes full of blood on the snowbank docks waiting for a door in the East River to open to a room full of steamheat and opium, who created great suicidal dramas on the apartment cliff-banks of the Hudson under the wartime blue floodlight of the moon & their heads shall be crowned with laurel in oblivion, who ate the lamb stew of the imagination or digested the crab at the muddy bottom of the rivers of Bowery, who wept at the romance of the streets with their pushcarts full of onions and bad music, who sat in boxes breathing in the darkness under the bridge, and rose up to build harpsichords in their lofts, who coughed on the sixth floor of Harlem crowned with flame under the tubercular sky surrounded by orange crates of theology, who scribbled all night rocking and rolling over lofty incantations which in the yellow morning were stanzas of gibberish, who cooked rotten animals lung heart feet tail borsht & tortillas dreaming of the pure vegetable kingdom, who plunged themselves under meat trucks looking for an egg, who threw their watches off the roof to cast their ballot for Eternity outside of Time, & alarm clocks fell on their heads every day for the next decade, who cut their wrists three times successively unsuccessfully, gave up and were forced to open antique stores where they thought they were growing old and cried, who were burned alive in their innocent flannel suits on Madison Avenue amid blasts of leaden verse & the tanked-up clatter of the iron regiments of fashion & the nitroglycerine shrieks of the fairies of advertising & the mustard gas of sinister intelligent editors, or were run down by the drunken taxicabs of Absolute Reality, who jumped off the Brooklyn Bridge this actually happened and walked away unknown and forgotten into the ghostly daze of Chinatown soup alley ways & firetrucks, not even one free beer, who sang out of their windows in despair, fell out of the subway window, jumped in the filthy Passaic, leaped on negroes, cried all over the street, danced on broken wineglasses barefoot smashed phonograph records of nostalgic European 1930s German jazz finished the whiskey and threw up groaning into the bloody toilet, moans in their ears and the blast of colossal steam whistles, who barreled down the highways of the past journeying to each other's hotrod-Golgotha jail-solitude watch or Birmingham jazz incarnation, who drove crosscountry seventytwo hours to find out if I had a vision or you had a vision or he had a vision to find out Eternity, who journeyed to Denver, who died in Denver, who came back to Denver & waited in vain, who watched over Denver & brooded & loned in Denver and finally went away to find out the Time, & now Denver is lonesome for her heroes, who fell on their knees in hopeless cathedrals praying for each other's salvation and light and breasts, until the soul illuminated its hair for a second, who crashed through their minds in jail waiting for impossible criminals with golden heads and the charm of reality in their hearts who sang sweet blues to Alcatraz, who retired to Mexico to cultivate a habit, or Rocky Mount to tender Buddha or Tangiers to boys or Southern Pacific to the black locomotive or Harvard to Narcissus to Woodlawn to the daisychain or grave, who demanded sanity trials accusing the radio of hyp notism & were left with their insanity & their hands & a hung jury, who threw potato salad at CCNY lecturers on Dadaism and subsequently presented themselves on the granite steps of the madhouse with shaven heads and harlequin speech of suicide, demanding instantaneous lobotomy, and who were given instead the concrete void of insulin Metrazol electricity hydrotherapy psychotherapy occupational therapy pingpong & amnesia, who in humorless protest overturned only one symbolic pingpong table, resting briefly in catatonia, returning years later truly bald except for a wig of blood, and tears and fingers, to the visible mad man doom of the wards of the madtowns of the East, Pilgrim State's Rockland's and Greystone's foetid halls, bickering with the echoes of the soul, rocking and rolling in the midnight solitude-bench dolmen-realms of love, dream of life a nightmare, bodies turned to stone as heavy as the moon, with mother finally ******, and the last fantastic book flung out of the tenement window, and the last door closed at 4. A.M. and the last telephone slammed at the wall in reply and the last furnished room emptied down to the last piece of mental furniture, a yellow paper rose twisted on a wire hanger in the closet, and even that imaginary, nothing but a hopeful little bit of hallucination--ah, Carl, while you are not safe I am not safe, and now you're really in the total animal soup of time--and who therefore ran through the icy streets obsessed with a sudden flash of the alchemy of the use of the ellipse the catalog the meter & the vibrating plane, who dreamt and made incarnate gaps in Time & Space through images juxtaposed, and trapped the archangel of the soul between 2 visual images and joined the elemental verbs and set the noun and dash of consciousness together jumping with sensation of Pater Omnipotens Aeterna Deus to recreate the syntax and measure of poor human prose and stand before you speechless and intelligent and shaking with shame, rejected yet confessing out the soul to conform to the rhythm of thought in his naked and endless head, the madman bum and angel beat in Time, unknown, yet putting down here what might be left to say in time come after death, and rose reincarnate in the ghostly clothes of jazz in the goldhorn shadow of the band and blew the suffering of America's naked mind for love into an eli eli lamma lamma sabacthani saxophone cry that shivered the cities down to the last radio with the absolute heart of the poem of life butchered out of their own bodies good to eat a thousand years.
II What sphinx of cement and aluminum bashed open their skulls and ate up their brains and imagination?
Moloch! Solitude! Filth! Ugliness! Ashcans and unob tainable dollars! Children screaming under the stairways! Boys sobbing in armies! Old men weeping in the parks!
Moloch! Moloch! Nightmare of Moloch! Moloch the loveless! Mental Moloch! Moloch the heavy judger of men!
Moloch the incomprehensible prison! Moloch the crossbone soulless jailhouse and Congress of sorrows! Moloch whose buildings are judgment!
Moloch the vast stone of war! Moloch the stunned governments!
Moloch whose mind is pure machinery! Moloch whose blood is running money! Moloch whose fingers are ten armies! Moloch whose breast is a cannibal dynamo! Moloch whose ear is a smoking tomb!
Moloch whose eyes are a thousand blind windows!
Moloch whose skyscrapers stand in the long streets like endless Jehovahs! Moloch whose factories dream and croak in the fog! Moloch whose smokestacks and antennae crown the cities!
Moloch whose love is endless oil and stone! Moloch whose soul is electricity and banks! Moloch whose poverty is the specter of genius! Moloch whose fate is a cloud of sexless hydrogen!
Moloch whose name is the Mind!
Moloch in whom I sit lonely! Moloch in whom I dream Angels! Crazy in Moloch! Cocksucker in Moloch! Lacklove and manless in Moloch!
Moloch who entered my soul early! Moloch in whom I am a consciousness without a body! Moloch who frightened me out of my natural ecstasy!
Moloch whom I abandon! Wake up in Moloch!
Light streaming out of the sky!
Moloch! Moloch! Robot apartments! invisible suburbs!
skeleton treasuries! blind capitals! demonic industries! spectral nations! invincible mad houses! granite cocks! monstrous bombs!
They broke their backs lifting Moloch to Heaven! Pavements, trees, radios, tons! lifting the city to Heaven which exists and is everywhere about us!
Visions! omens! hallucinations! miracles! ecstasies!
gone down the American river!
Dreams! adorations! illuminations! religions! the whole boatload of sensitive bullshit!
Breakthroughs! over the river! flips and crucifixions!
gone down the flood! Highs! Epiphanies! Despairs! Ten years' animal screams and suicides!
Minds! New loves! Mad generation! down on the rocks of Time!
Real holy laughter in the river! They saw it all! the wild eyes! the holy yells! They bade farewell!
They jumped off the roof! to solitude! waving!
carrying flowers! Down to the river! into the street!
IIICarl Solomon! I'm with you in Rockland where you're madder than I am I'm with you in Rockland where you must feel very strange I'm with you in Rockland where you imitate the shade of my mother I'm with you in Rockland where you've murdered your twelve secretaries I'm with you in Rockland where you laugh at this invisible humor I'm with you in Rockland where we are great writers on the same dreadful typewriter I'm with you in Rockland where your condition has become serious and is reported on the radio I'm with you in Rockland where the faculties of the skull no longer admit the worms of the senses I'm with you in Rockland where you drink the tea of the breasts of the spinsters of Utica I'm with you in Rockland where you pun on the bodies of your nurses the harpies of the Bronx I'm with you in Rockland where you scream in a straightjacket that you're losing the game of the actual pingpong of the abyss I'm with you in Rockland where you bang on the catatonic piano the soul is innocent and immortal it should never die ungodly in an armed madhouse I'm with you in Rockland where fifty more shocks will never return your soul to its body again from its pilgrimage to a cross in the void I'm with you in Rockland where you accuse your doctors of insanity and plot the Hebrew socialist revolution against the fascist national Golgotha I'm with you in Rockland where you will split the heavens of Long Island and resurrect your living human Jesus from the superhuman tomb I'm with you in Rockland where there are twenty-five-thousand mad comrades all together singing the final stanzas of the Internationale I'm with you in Rockland where we hug and kiss the United States under our bedsheets the United States that coughs all night and won't let us sleep I'm with you in Rockland where we wake up electrified out of the coma by our own souls' airplanes roaring over the roof they've come to drop angelic bombs the hospital illuminates itself  imaginary walls collapse   O skinny legions run outside  O starry spangled shock of mercy the eternal war is here   O victory forget your underwear we're free I'm with you in Rockland in my dreams you walk dripping from a seajourney on the highway across America in tears to the door of my cottage in the Western night America I've given you all and now I'm nothing.
America two dollars and twentyseven cents January 17, 1956.
I can't stand my own mind.
America when will we end the human war?
Go fuck yourself with your atom bomb.
I don't feel good don't bother me.
I won't write my poem till I'm in my right mind.
America when will you be angelic?
When will you take off your clothes?
When will you look at yourself through the grave?
When will you be worthy of your million Trotskyites?
America why are your libraries full of tears?
America when will you send your eggs to India?
I'm sick of your insane demands.
When can I go into the supermarket and buy what I need with my good looks?
America after all it is you and I who are perfect not the next world.
Your machinery is too much for me.
You made me want to be a saint.
There must be some other way to settle this argument.
Burroughs is in Tangiers I don't think he'll come back it's sinister.
Are you being sinister or is this some form of practical joke?
I'm trying to come to the point.
I refuse to give up my obsession.
America stop pushing I know what I'm doing.
America the plum blossoms are falling.
I haven't read the newspapers for months, everyday somebody goes on trial for murder.
America I feel sentimental about the Wobblies.
America I used to be a communist when I was a kid I'm not sorry.
I smoke marijuana every chance I get.
I sit in my house for days on end and stare at the roses in the closet.
When I go to Chinatown I get drunk and never get laid.
My mind is made up there's going to be trouble.
You should have seen me reading Marx.
My psychoanalyst thinks I'm perfectly right.
I won't say the Lord's Prayer.
I have mystical visions and cosmic vibrations.
America I still haven't told you what you did to Uncle Max after he came over from Russia.I'm addressing you.
Are you going to let your emotional life be run by Time Magazine?
I'm obsessed by Time Magazine.
I read it every week.
Its cover stares at me every time I slink past the corner candystore.
I read it in the basement of the Berkeley Public Library.
It's always telling me about responsibility. Business-men are serious. Movie producers are serious.
Everybody's serious but me.
It occurs to me that I am America.
I am talking to myself again.
Asia is rising against me.
I haven't got a chinaman's chance.
I'd better consider my national resources.
My national resources consist of two joints of marijuana millions of genitals an unpublishable private literature that goes 1400 miles an hour and twenty-five-thousand mental institutions.
I say nothing about my prisons nor the millions of underprivileged who live in my flowerpots under the light of five hundred suns.
I have abolished the whorehouses of France, Tangiers is the next to go.
My ambition is to be President despite the fact that I'm a Catholic.
America how can I write a holy litany in your silly mood?
I will continue like Henry Ford my strophes are as individual as his automobiles more so they're all different sexes.
America I will sell you strophes $2500 apiece $500 down on your old strophe America free Tom Mooney America save the Spanish Loyalists America Sacco & Vanzetti must not die America I am the Scottsboro boys.
America when I was seven momma took me to Com-munist Cell meetings they sold us garbanzos a handful per ticket a ticket costs a nickel and the speeches were free everybody was angelic and sentimental about the workers it was all so sin-cere you have no idea what a good thing the party was in 1835 Scott Nearing was a grand old man a real mensch Mother Bloor made me cry I once saw Israel Amter plain. Everybody must have been a spy.
America you don't really want to go to war.
America it's them bad Russians.
Them Russians them Russians and them Chinamen.
And them Russians.
The Russia wants to eat us alive. The Russia's power mad. She wants to take our cars from out our garages.
Her wants to grab Chicago. Her needs a Red Readers' Digest. Her wants our auto plants in Siberia.
Him big bureaucracy running our fillingsta-tions.
That no good. Ugh. Him make Indians learn read.
Him need big black niggers. Hah. Her make us all work sixteen hours a day. Help.
America this is quite serious.
America this is the impression I get from looking in the television set.
America is this correct?
I'd better get right down to the job.
It's true I don't want to join the Army or turn lathes in precision parts factories, I'm nearsighted and psychopathic anyway.
America I'm putting my queer shoulder to the wheel.
What thoughts I have of you tonight, Walt Whitman, for I walked down the sidestreets under the trees with a headache self-conscious looking at the full moon.
In my hungry fatigue, and shopping for images, I went into the neon fruit supermarket, dreaming of your enumerations!
What peaches and what penumbras! Whole families shopping at night! Aisles full of husbands! Wives in the avocados, babies in the tomatoes!--and you, Garcнa Lorca, what were you doing down by the watermelons?
I saw you, Walt Whitman, childless, lonely old grubber, poking among the meats in the refrigerator and eyeing the grocery boys.
I heard you asking questions of each: Who killed the pork chops? What price bananas? Are you my Angel?
I wandered in and out of the brilliant stacks of cans following you, and followed in my imagination by the store detective.
We strode down the open corridors together in our solitary fancy tasting artichokes, possessing every frozen delicacy, and never passing the cashier.
Where are we going, Walt Whitman? The doors close in an hour. Which way does your beard point tonight?
(I touch your book and dream of our odyssey in the supermarket and feel absurd.) Will we walk all night through solitary streets?
The trees add shade to shade, lights out in the houses, we'll both be lonely.
Will we stroll dreaming ofthe lost America of love past blue automobiles in driveways, home to our silent cottage?
Ah, dear father, graybeard, lonely old courageteacher, what America did you have when Charon quit poling his ferry and you got out on a smoking bank and stood watching the boat disappear on the black waters of Lethe?
Homage Kenneth KochIf I were doing my Laundry I'd wash my dirty IranI'd throw in my United States, and pour on the Ivory Soap,scrub up Africa, put all the birds and elephants back inthe jungle,I'd wash the Amazon river and clean the oily Carib & Gulf of Mexico,Rub that smog off the North Pole, wipe up all the pipelines in Alaska,Rub a dub dub for Rocky Flats and Los Alamos, Flush that sparklyCesium out of Love CanalRinse down the Acid Rain over the Parthenon & Sphinx, Drain the Sludgeout of the Mediterranean basin & make it azure again,Put some blueing back into the sky over the Rhine, bleach the littleClouds so snow return white as snow,Cleanse the Hudson Thames & Neckar, Drain the Suds out of Lake ErieThen I'd throw big Asia in one giant Load & wash out the blood &Agent Orange,Dump the whole mess of Russia and China in the wringer, squeeze outthe tattletail Gray of U.S. Central American police state,& put the planet in the drier & let it sit 20 minutes or anI speak of love that comes to mind:The moon is faithful, although blind;She moves in thought she cannot speak.Perfect care has made her bleak.I never dreamed the sea so deep,The earth so dark; so long my sleep,I have become another child.When I died, love, when I diedmy heart was broken in your care;I never suffered love so fairas now I suffer and abidewhen I died, love, when I died.When I died, love, when I diedI wearied in an endless mazethat men have walked for centuries,as endless as the gate was widewhen I died, love, when I died.When I died, love, when I diedthere was a war in the upper air:all that happens, happens there;there was an angel by my sideI walked on the banks of the tincan banana dock and sat down under the huge shade of a Southern Pacific locomotive to look at the sunset over the box house hills and cry.
Jack Kerouac sat beside me on a busted rusty iron pole, companion, we thought the same thoughts of the soul, bleak and blue and sad-eyed, surrounded by the gnarled steel roots of trees of machinery.
The oily water on the river mirrored the red sky, sun sank on top of final Frisco peaks, no fish in that stream, no hermit in those mounts, just ourselves rheumy-eyed and hungover like old bums on the riverbank, tired and wily.
Look at the Sunflower, he said, there was a dead gray shadow against the sky, big as a man, sitting dry on top of a pile of ancient sawdust---I rushed up enchanted--it was my first sunflower, memories of Blake--my visions--Harlem and Hells of the Eastern rivers, bridges clanking Joes Greasy Sandwiches, dead baby carriages, black treadless tires forgotten and unretreaded, the poem of the riverbank, condoms & pots, steel knives, nothing stainless, only the dank muck and the razor-sharp artifacts passing into the past-and the gray Sunflower poised against the sunset, crackly bleak and dusty with the smut and smog and smoke of olden locomotives in its eye-corolla of bleary spikes pushed down and broken like a battered crown, seeds fallen out of its face, soon-to-be-toothless mouth of sunny air, sunrays obliterated on its hairy head like a dried wire spiderweb, leaves stuck out like arms out of the stem, gestures from the sawdust root, broke pieces of plaster fallen out of the black twigs, a dead fly in its ear, Unholy battered old thing you were, my sunflower O my soul, I loved you then!
The grime was no man's grime but death and human locomotives, all that dress of dust, that veil of darkened railroad skin, that smog of cheek, that eyelid of black mis'ry, that sooty hand or phallus or protuberance of artificial worse-than-dirt--industrial-modern--all that civilization spotting your crazy golden crown-and those blear thoughts of death and dusty loveless eyes and ends and withered roots below, in the home-pile of sand and sawdust, rubber dollar bills, skin of machinery, the guts and innards of the weeping coughing car, the empty lonely tincans with their rusty tongues alack, what more could I name, the smoked ashes of some cock cigar, the cunts of wheelbarrows and the milky breasts of cars, wornout asses out of chairs & sphincters of dynamos--all these entangled in your mummied roots--and you there standing before me in the sunset, all your glory in your form!
A perfect beauty of a sunflower! a perfect excellent lovely sunflower existence! a sweet natural eye to the new hip moon, woke up alive and excited grasping in the sunset shadow sunrise golden monthly breeze!
How many flies buzzed round you innocent of your grime, while you cursed the heavens of the railroad and your flower soul?
Poor dead flower? when did you forget you were a flower? when did you look at your skin and decide you were an impotent dirty old locomotive? the ghost of a locomotive? the specter and shade of a once powerful mad American locomotive?
You were never no locomotive, Sunflower, you were a sunflower!
And you Locomotive, you are a locomotive, forget me not!
So I grabbed up the skeleton thick sunflower and stuck it at my side like a scepter, and deliver my sermon to my soul, and Jack's soul too, and anyone who'll listen, --We're not our skin of grime, we're not our dread bleak dusty imageless locomotive, we're all beautiful golden sunflowers inside, we're blessed by our own seed & golden hairy naked accomplishment-bodies growing into mad black formal sunflowers in the sunset, spied on by our eyes under the shadow of the mad locomotive riverbank sunset Frisco hilly tincan evening sitdown vision.
The weight of the world is love.
Under the burden of solitude, under the burden of dissatisfaction the weight, the weight we carry is love.
Who can deny?
In dreams it touches the body, in thought constructs a miracle, in imagination anguishes till born in human-looks out of the heart burning with purity-for the burden of life is love, but we carry the weight wearily, and so must rest in the arms of love at last, must rest in the arms of love.
No rest without love, no sleep without dreams of love-be mad or chill obsessed with angels or machines, the final wish is love --cannot be bitter, cannot deny, cannot withhold if denied: the weight is too heavy --must give for no return as thought is given in solitude in all the excellence of its excess.
The warm bodies shine together in the darkness, the hand moves to the center of the flesh, the skin trembles in happiness and the soul comes joyful to the eye-yes, yes, that's what I wanted, I always wanted, I always wanted, to return to the body where I was born.
Please master can I touch your cheeckplease master can I kneel at  your feetplease master can I loosen your blue pantsplease master can I gaze at your golden haired bellyplease master can I have your thighs bare to my eyesplease master can I take off my clothes below your chairplease master can I can I kiss your ankles and soulplease master can I touch lips to your hard muscle hairless thighplease master can I lay my ear pressed to your stomachplease master can I wrap my arms around your white assplease master can I lick your groin gurled with blond soft furplease master can I touch my tongue to your rosy assholeplease master may I pass my face to your balls,please master order me down on the floor,please master tell me to lick your thick shaftplease master put your rough hands on my bald hairy skullplease master press my mouth to your prick-heartplease master press my face into your belly, pull me slowly strong thumbedtill your dumb hardness fills my throat to the basetill I swallow and taste your delicate flesh-hot prick barrel veined PleaseMater push my shoulders away and stare in my eyes, & make me bend over the tableplease master grab my thighs and lift my ass to your waistplease master your hand's rough stroke on my neck your palm down to mybacksideplease master push me, my feet on chairs, till my hole feels the breath of your spit and your thumb strokeplease master make my say Please Master Fuck me now PleaseMaster grease my balls and hairmouth with sweet vaselinesplease master stroke your shaft with white creamsplease master touch your cock head to my wrinkled self-holeplease master push it in gently, your elbows enwrapped round my breastyour arms passing down to my belly, my penis you touch w/ your fingersplease master shove it in me a little, a little, a little,please master sink your droor thing down my behind& please master make me wiggle my rear to eat up the prick trunktill my asshalfs cuddle your thighs, my back bent over,till I'm alone sticking out, your sword stuck throbbing in meplease master pull out and slowly roll onto the bottomplease master lunge it again, and withdraw the tipplease please master fuck me again with your self, please fuck me PleaseMaster drive down till it hurts me the softness theSoftness please master make love to my ass, give body to center, & fuck mefor good like a girl,tenderly clasp me please master I take me to thee,& drive in my belly your selfsame sweet heat-roodyou fingered in solitude Denver or Brooklyn or fucked in a maiden in Pariscarlotsplease master drive me thy vehicle, body of love drops, sweat fuckbody of tenderness, Give me your dogh fuck fasterplease master make me go moan on the tableGo moan O please master do fuck me like thatin your rhythm thrill-plunge & pull-back-bounce & push downtill I loosen my asshole a dog on the table yelping with terror delight to belovedPlease master call me a dog, an ass beast, a wet asshole, & fuck me more violent, my eyes hid with your palms round my skull& plunge down in a brutal hard lash thru soft drip-fish& throb thru five seconds to spurt out your semen heatover & over, bamming it in while I cry out your name I do love youplease Master.
When I dieI don't care what happens to my bodythrow ashes in the air, scatter 'em in East Riverbury an urn in Elizabeth New Jersey, B'nai Israel CemeteryBut l want a big funeralSt. Patrick's Cathedral, St. Mark's Church, the largest synagogue in ManhattanFirst, there's family, brother, nephews, spry aged Edith stepmother 96, Aunt Honey from old Newark,Doctor Joel, cousin Mindy, brother Gene one eyed one ear'd, sister-in-law blonde Connie, five nephews, stepbrothers & sisters their grandchildren,companion Peter Orlovsky, caretakers Rosenthal & Hale, Bill Morgan--Next, teacher Trungpa Vajracharya's ghost mind, Gelek Rinpoche, there Sakyong Mipham, Dalai Lama alert, chance visiting America, Satchitananda Swami Shivananda, Dehorahava Baba, Karmapa XVI, Dudjom Rinpoche, Katagiri & Suzuki Roshi's phantomsBaker, Whalen, Daido Loorie, Qwong, Frail White-haired Kapleau Roshis, Lama Tarchen --Then, most important, lovers over half-centuryDozens, a hundred, more, older fellows bald & richyoung boys met naked recently in bed, crowds surprised to see each other, innumerable, intimate, exchanging memories"He taught me to meditate, now I'm an old veteran of the thousandday retreat --""I played music on subway platforms, I'm straight but loved him he loved me""I felt more love from him at 19 than ever from anyone""We'd lie under covers gossip, read my poetry, hug & kiss belly to belly arms round each other""I'd always get into his bed with underwear on & by morning my skivvies would be on the floor""Japanese, always wanted take it up my bum with a master""We'd talk all night about Kerouac & Cassady sit Buddhalike then sleep in his captain's bed.""He seemed to need so much affection, a shame not to make him happy""I was lonely never in bed nude with anyone before, he was so gentle my stomachshuddered when he traced his finger along my abdomen nipple to hips-- ""All I did was lay back eyes closed, he'd bring me to come with mouth & fingers along my waist""He gave great head"So there be gossip from loves of 1948, ghost of Neal Cassady commin-gling with flesh and youthful blood of 1997and surprise -- "You too? But I thought you were straight!""I am but Ginsberg an exception, for some reason he pleased me.""I forgot whether I was straight gay queer or funny, was myself, tender and affectionate to be kissed on the top of my head,my forehead throat heart & solar plexus, mid-belly. on my prick, tickled with his tongue my behind""I loved the way he'd recite 'But at my back allways hear/ time's winged chariot hurrying near,' heads together, eye to eye, on a pillow --"Among lovers one handsome youth straggling the rear"I studied his poetry class, 17 year-old kid, ran some errands to his walk-up flat,seduced me didn't want to, made me come, went home, never saw him again never wanted to... ""He couldn't get it up but loved me," "A clean old man." "He made sure I came first"This the crowd most surprised proud at ceremonial place of honor--Then poets & musicians -- college boys' grunge bands -- age-old rock star Beatles, faithful guitar accompanists, gay classical con-ductors, unknown high Jazz music composers, funky trum-peters, bowed bass & french horn black geniuses, folksinger fiddlers with dobro tamborine harmonica mandolin auto-harp pennywhistles & kazoosNext, artist Italian romantic realists schooled in mystic 60's India, Late fauve Tuscan painter-poets, Classic draftsman Massa-chusets surreal jackanapes with continental wives, poverty sketchbook gesso oil watercolor masters from American provincesThen highschool teachers, lonely Irish librarians, delicate biblio-philes, sex liberation troops nay armies, ladies of either sex"I met him dozens of times he never remembered my name I loved him anyway, true artist""Nervous breakdown after menopause, his poetry humor saved me from suicide hospitals""Charmant, genius with modest manners, washed sink, dishes my studio guest a week in Budapest"Thousands of readers, "Howl changed my life in Libertyville Illinois""I saw him read Montclair State Teachers College decided be a poet-- ""He turned me on, I started with garage rock sang my songs in Kansas City""Kaddish made me weep for myself & father alive in Nevada City""Father Death comforted me when my sister died Boston l982""I read what he said in a newsmagazine, blew my mind, realized others like me out there"Deaf & Dumb bards with hand signing quick brilliant gesturesThen Journalists, editors's secretaries, agents, portraitists & photo-graphy aficionados, rock critics, cultured laborors, cultural historians come to witness the historic funeralSuper-fans, poetasters, aging Beatnicks & Deadheads, autograph-hunters, distinguished paparazzi, intelligent gawkersEveryone knew they were part of 'History" except the deceasedwho never knew exactly what was happening even when I was alive"Soyez muette pour moi, Idole contemplative..."I came home and found a lion in my living roomRushed out on the fire escape screaming Lion! Lion!Two stenographers pulled their brunnette hair and banged the window shutI hurried home to Patterson and stayed two daysCalled up old Reichian analystwho'd kicked me out of therapy for smoking marijuana'It's happened' I panted 'There's a Lion in my living room''I'm afraid any discussion would have no value' he hung upI went to my old boyfriend we got drunk with his girlfriendI kissed him and announced I had a lion with a mad gleam in my eyeWe wound up fighting on the floor I bit his eyebrow he kicked me outI ended up masturbating in his jeep parked in the street moaning 'Lion.'Found Joey my novelist friend and roared at him 'Lion!'He looked at me interested and read me his spontaneous ignu high poetriesI listened for lions all I heard was Elephant Tiglon Hippogriff UnicornAntsBut figured he really understood me when we made it in Ignaz Wisdom's bathroom.But next day he sent me a leaf from his Smoky Mountain retreat'I love you little Bo-Bo with your delicate golden lionsBut there being no Self and No Bars therefore the Zoo of your dear Fatherhath no lionYou said your mother was mad don't expect me to produce the Monster foryour Bridegroom.'Confused dazed and exalted bethought me of real lion starved in his stinkin HarlemOpened the door the room was filled with the bomb blast of his angerHe roaring hungrily at the plaster walls but nobody could hear outsidethru the windowMy eye caught the edge of the red neighbor apartment building standing indeafening stillnessWe gazed at each other his implacable yellow eye in the red halo of furWaxed rhuemy on my own but he stopped roaring and bared a fanggreeting.I turned my back and cooked broccoli for supper on an iron gas stoveboilt water and took a hot bath in the old tup under the sink board.He didn't eat me, tho I regretted him starving in my presence.Next week he wasted away a sick rug full of bones wheaten hair falling outenraged and reddening eye as he lay aching huge hairy head on his pawsby the egg-crate bookcase filled up with thin volumes of Plato, & Buddha.Sat by his side every night averting my eyes from his hungry motheatenfacestopped eating myself he got weaker and roared at night while I had nightmaresEaten by lion in bookstore on Cosmic Campus, a lion myself starved byProfessor Kandisky, dying in a lion's flophouse circus,I woke up mornings the lion still added dying on the floor--'TerriblePresence!'I cried'Eat me or die!'It got up that afternoon--walked to the door with its paw on the south wall tosteady its trembling bodyLet out a soul-rending creak from the bottomless roof of his mouththundering from my floor to heaven heavier than a volcano at night inMexicoPushed the door open and said in a gravelly voice "Not this time Baby--but I will be back again."Lion that eats my mind now for a decade knowing only your hungerNot the bliss of your satisfaction O roar of the universe how am I chosenIn this life I have heard your promise I am ready to die I have servedYour starved and ancient Presence O Lord I wait in my room at yourMercy.The air is dark, the night is sad,I lie sleepless and I groan.Nobody cares when a man goes mad:He is sorry, God is glad.Shadow changes into bone.Every shadow has a name;When I think of mine I moan,I hear rumors of such fame.Not for pride, but only shame,Shadow changes into bone.When I blush I weep for joy,And laughter drops from me like a stone:The aging laughter of the boyTo see the ageless dead so coy.Kissass is the Part of PeaceAmerica will have to Kissass Mother EarthWhites have to Kissass Blacks, for Peace & Pleasure,Drinking my teaWithout sugar-No difference.The sparrow shitsupside down--ah! my brain & eggsMayan head in aPacific driftwood bole--Someday I'll live in N.Y.Looking over my shouldermy behind was coveredwith cherry blossoms.Winter HaikuI didn't know the names of the flowers--nowmy garden is gone.I slapped the mosquitoand missed.What made me do that?Reading haikuI am unhappy,longing for the Nameless.A frog floating in the drugstore jar:summer rain on grey pavements.(after Shiki)On the porchin my shorts;auto lights in the rain.Another yearhas past-the worldis no different.The first thing I looked for in my old garden wasThe Cherry Tree.My old desk:the first thing I looked forin my house.My early journal:the first thing I foundin my old desk.My mother's ghost:the first thing I foundin the living room.I quit shavingbut the eyes that glanced at meremained in the mirror.The madman emerges from the movies:the street at lunchtime.Cities of boysare in their graves,and in this town...Lying on my sidein the void:the breath in my nose.On the fifteenth floorthe dog chews a bone-Screech of taxicabs.A hardon in New York,a boyin San Fransisco.The moon over the roof,worms in the garden.I rent this house.[Haiku composed in the backyard cottage at 1624Milvia Street, Berkeley 1955, while reading R.H.
Now mind is clearas a cloudless sky.Time then to make ahome in wilderness.What have I done butwander with my eyesin the trees? So I will build:  wife,family, and seekfor neighbors.Or Iperish of lonesomenessor want of food orlightning or the bear(must tame the hartand wear the bear).And maybe make an imageof my wandering, a littleimage—shrine by theroadside to signifyto traveler that I livehere in the wildernessElan that lifts me above the cloudsinto pure space, timeless, yea eternalBreath transmuted into wordsTransmuted back to breathin one hundred two hundred yearsnearly Immortal, Sappho's 26 centuriesof cadenced breathing -- beyond time, clocks, empires, bodies, cars,chariots, rocket ships skyscrapers, Nation empiresbrass walls, polished marble, Inca Artworkof the mind -- but where's it come from?Inspiration?  The muses drawing breath for you?  God?Nah, don't believe it, you'll get entangled in Heaven or Hell --Guilt power, that makes the heart beat wake all nightflooding mind with space, echoing through future cities, Megalopolis orCretan village, Zeus' birth cave Lassithi Plains -- Otsego Countyfarmhouse, Kansas front porch?Buddha's a help, promises ordinary mind no nirvana --coffee, alcohol, cocaine, mushrooms, marijuana, laughing gas?Nope, too heavy for this lightness lifts the brain into blue skyat May dawn when birds start singing on East 12th street --Where does it come from, where does it go forever?Hey Father Death, I'm flying homeHey poor man, you're all aloneHey old daddy, I know where I'm goingFather Death, Don't cry any moreMama's there, underneath the floorBrother Death, please mind the storeOld Aunty Death  Don't hide your bonesOld Uncle Death  I hear your groansO Sister Death  how sweet your moansO Children Deaths go breathe your breathsSobbing breasts'll ease your DeathsPain is gone, tears take the restGenius Death  your art is doneLover Death  your body's goneFather Death  I'm coming homeGuru Death your words are trueTeacher Death I do thank youFor inspiring me to sing this BluesBuddha Death, I wake with youDharma Death, your mind is newSangha Death, we'll work it throughSuffering is what was bornIgnorance made me forlornTearful truths I cannot scornFather Breath once more farewellBirth you gave was no thing illMy heart is still, as time will tell.railroad yard in San Jose I wandered desolate in front of a tank factory and sat on a bench near the switchman's shack.
A flower lay on the hay on the asphalt highway --the dread hay flower I thought--It had a brittle black stem and corolla of yellowish dirty spikes like Jesus' inchlong crown, and a soiled dry center cotton tuft like a used shaving brush that's been lying under the garage for a year.
Yellow, yellow flower, and flower of industry, tough spiky ugly flower, flower nonetheless, with the form of the great yellow Rose in your brain!
This is the flower of the World.  Last nite I dreamed of T.S. Eliotwelcoming me to the land of dreamSofas couches fog in EnglandTea in his digs Chelsea rainbowscurtains on his windows, fog seeping inthe chimney but a nice warm house and an incredibly sweet hooknosedEliot he loved me, put me up,gave me a couch to sleep on,conversed kindly, took me seriousasked my opinion on MayakovskyI read him Corso Creeley Kerouacadvised Burroughs Olson Hunckethe bearded lady in the Zoo, theintelligent puma in Mexico City6 chorus boys from Zanzibarwho chanted in wornout polygotSwahili, and the rippling rythymsof Ma Rainey and Vachel Lindsay.On the Isle of the Queenwe had a long evening's conversationThen he tucked me in my long red underwear under a silken blanket by the fire on the sofagave me English Hottieand went off sadly to his bed,Saying ah Ginsberg I am gladto have met a fine young man like you.At last, I woke ashamed of myself.Is he that good and kind? Am I that great?What's my motive dreaming his manna? What English Departmentwould that impress? What failureto be perfect prophet's made up here?I dream of my kindness to T.S. Eliotwanting to be a historical poetand share in his finance of Imagery-overambitious dream of eccentric boy.God forbid my evil dreams come true.Last nite I dreamed of Allen Ginsberg.Holy! Holy! Holy! Holy! Holy! Holy! Holy! Holy! Holy!
Holy! Holy! Holy! Holy! Holy! Holy!
The world is holy! The soul is holy! The skin is holy!
The nose is holy! The tongue and cock and hand and asshole holy!
Everything is holy! everybody's holy! everywhere is holy! everyday is in eternity! Everyman's an angel!
The bum's as holy as the seraphim! the madman is holy as you my soul are holy!
The typewriter is holy the poem is holy the voice is holy the hearers are holy the ecstasy is holy!
Holy Peter holy Allen holy Solomon holy Lucien holy Kerouac holy Huncke holy Burroughs holy Cassady holy the unknown buggered and suffering beggars holy the hideous human angels!
Holy my mother in the insane asylum! Holy the cocks of the grandfathers of Kansas!
Holy the groaning saxophone! Holy the bop apocalypse! Holy the jazzbands marijuana hipsters peace & junk & drums!
Holy the solitudes of skyscrapers and pavements! Holy the cafeterias filled with the millions! Holy the mysterious rivers of tears under the streets!
Holy the lone juggernaut! Holy the vast lamb of the middle class! Holy the crazy shepherds of rebellion! Who digs Los Angeles IS Los Angeles!
Holy New York Holy San Francisco Holy Peoria & Seattle Holy Paris Holy Tangiers Holy Moscow Holy Istanbul!
Holy time in eternity holy eternity in time holy the clocks in space holy the fourth dimension holy the fifth International holy the Angel in Moloch!
Holy the sea holy the desert holy the railroad holy the locomotive holy the visions holy the hallucinations holy the miracles holy the eyeball holy the abyss!
Holy forgiveness! mercy! charity! faith! Holy! Ours!
bodies! suffering! magnanimity!
Holy the supernatural extra brilliant intelligent kindness of the soul!
Millions of babies watching the skiesBellies swollen, with big round eyesOn Jessore Road--long bamboo hutsNoplace to shit but sand channel rutsMillions of fathers in rainMillions of mothers in painMillions of brothers in woeMillions of sisters nowhere to goOne Million aunts are dying for breadOne Million uncles lamenting the deadGrandfather millions homeless and sadGrandmother millions silently madMillions of daughters walk in the mudMillions of children wash in the floodA Million girls vomit & groanMillions of families hopeless aloneMillions of souls nineteenseventyonehomeless on Jessore road under grey sunA million are dead, the million who canWalk toward Calcutta from East PakistanTaxi September along Jessore RoadOxcart skeletons drag charcoal loadpast watery fields thru rain flood rutsDung cakes on treetrunks, plastic-roof hutsWet processions   Families walkStunted boys    big heads don't talkLook bony skulls   & silent round eyesStarving black angels in human disguiseMother squats weeping & points to her sonsStanding thin legged    like elderly nunssmall bodied    hands to their mouths in prayerFive months small food    since they settled thereon one floor mat   with small empty potFather lifts up his hands at their lotTears come to their mother's eyePain makes mother Maya cryTwo children together    in palmroof shadeStare at me   no word is saidRice ration, lentils   one time a weekMilk powder for warweary infants meekNo vegetable money or work for the manRice lasts four days    eat while they canThen children starve    three days in a rowand vomit their next food   unless they eat slow.On Jessore road    Mother wept at my kneesBengali tongue    cried mister PleaseIdentity card    torn up on the floorHusband still waits    at the camp office doorBaby at play I was washing the floodNow they won't give us any more foodThe pieces are here in my celluloid purseInnocent baby play    our death curse Two policemen surrounded     by thousands of boysCrowded waiting    their daily bread joysCarry big whistles    & long bamboo sticksto whack them in line    They play hungry tricksBreaking the line   and jumping in front Into the circle    sneaks one skinny runtTwo brothers dance forward    on the mud stageTeh gaurds blow their whistles    & chase them in rageWhy are these infants    massed in this placeLaughing in play    & pushing for spaceWhy do they wait here so cheerful   & dreadWhy this is the House where they give children breadThe man in the bread door   Cries & comes outThousands of boys and girls    Take up his shoutIs it joy? is it prayer?    "No more bread today"Thousands of Children  at once scream "Hooray!"Run home to tents    where elders awaitMessenger children   with bread from the stateNo bread more today! & and no place to squatPainful baby, sick shit he has got.Malnutrition skulls thousands for monthsDysentery drains    bowels all at onceNurse shows disease card    EnterostrepSuspension is wanting    or else chlorostrepRefugee camps    in hospital shacksNewborn lay naked    on mother's thin lapsMonkeysized week old    Rheumatic babe eyeGastoenteritis Blood Poison    thousands must dieSeptember Jessore    Road rickshaw50,000 souls   in one camp I sawRows of bamboo    huts in the flood Open drains, & wet families waiting for foodBorder trucks flooded, food cant get past,American Angel machine   please come fast!Where is Ambassador Bunker today?Are his Helios machinegunning children at play?Where are the helicopters of U.S. AID?Smuggling dope in Bangkok's green shade.Where is America's Air Force of Light?Bombing North Laos all day and all night?Where are the President's Armies of Gold?Billionaire Navies    merciful Bold?Bringing us medicine    food and relief?Napalming North Viet Nam    and causing more grief?Where are our tears?  Who weeps for the pain?Where can these families go in the rain?Jessore Road's children close their big eyesWhere will we sleep when Our Father dies?Whom shall we pray to for rice and for care?Who can bring bread to this shit flood foul'd lair?Millions of children alone in the rain!Millions of children weeping in pain!Ring O ye tongues of the world for their woeRing out ye voices for Love we don't knowRing out ye bells of electrical painRing in the conscious of America brainHow many children are we who are lostWhose are these daughters we see turn to ghost?What are our souls that we have lost care?Ring out ye musics and weep if you dare--Cries in the mud by the thatch'd house sand drainSleeps in huge pipes in the wet shit-field rainwaits by the pump well, Woe to the world!whose children still starve    in their mother's arms curled.Is this what I did to myself in the past?What shall I do Sunil Poet I asked?Move on and leave them without any coins?What should I care for the love of my loins?What should we care for our cities and cars?What shall we buy with our Food Stamps on Mars?How many millions sit down in New York& sup this night's table on bone & roast pork?How many millions of beer cans are tossedin Oceans of Mother? How much does She cost?Cigar gasolines and   asphalt car dreamsStinking the world and dimming star beams--Finish the war in your breast    with a sighCome tast the tears    in your own Human eyePity us millions of phantoms you seeStarved in Samsara   on planet TVHow many millions of children die morebefore our Good Mothers perceive the Great Lord?How many good fathers pay tax to rebuild Armed forces that boast    the children they've killed?How many souls walk through Maya in painHow many babes    in illusory pain?How many families   hollow eyed  lost?How many grandmothers    turning to ghost?How many loves who never get bread?How many Aunts with holes in their head?How many sisters skulls on the ground?How many grandfathers   make no more sound?How many fathers in woeHow many sons   nowhere to go?How many daughters    nothing to eat?How many uncles   with swollen sick feet?Millions of babies in painMillions of mothers in rainMillions of brothers in woeMillions of children    nowhere to goI came home and found a lion in my room...[First draft of "The Lion for Real" CP 174-175]A lion met Americain the roadthey stared at each othertwo figures on the crossroads in the desert.America screamedThe lion roaredThey leaped at each otherAmerica desperate to winFighting with bombs, flamethrowers,knives forks submarines.The lion ate America, bit off her headand loped off to the golden hillsthat's all there is to sayabout america except that now she's LentoYou'll bare your bones you'll grow you'll pray you'll only knowWhen the light appears, boy, when the light appearsYou'll sing & you'll love you'll praise blue heavens aboveWhen the light appears, boy, when the light appearsYou'll whimper & you'll cry you'll get yourself sick and sighYou'll sleep & you'll dream you'll only know what you meanWhen the light appears, boy, when the light appearsYou'll come & you'll go, you'll wander to and froYou'll go home in despair you'll wonder why'd you careYou'll stammer & you'll lie you'll ask everybody whyYou'll cough and you'll pout you'll kick your toe with goutYou'll jump you'll shout you'll knock you're friends aboutYou'll bawl and you'll deny & announce your eyes are dryYou'll roll and you'll rock you'll show your big hard cockYou'll love and you'll grieve & one day you'll come believeAs you whistle & you smile the lord made you worthwhileYou'll preach and you'll glide on the pulpit in your prideSneak & slide across the stage like a river in high tideYou'll come fast or come on slow just the same you'll never knowWhen the light appears, boy, when the light appearsCool black night thru redwoodscars parked outside in shadebehind the gate, stars dim abovethe ravine, a fire burning by the sideporch and a few tired souls hunched overin black leather jackets.  In the hugewooden house, a yellow chandelier at 3 A.M. the blast of loudspeakershi-fi Rolling Stones Ray Charles BeatlesJumping Joe Jackson and twenty youthsdancing to the vibration thru the floor,a little weed in the bathroom, girls in scarlettights, one muscular smooth skinned mansweating dancing for hours, beer cansbent littering the yard, a hanged mansculpture dangling from a high creek branch,children sleeping softly in their bedroom bunks.And 4 police cars parked outside the paintedgate, red lights revolving in the leaves.Blandly mother takes him strolling by railroad and by river --he's the son of the absconded hot rod angel-and he imagines cars and rides them in his dreams, so lonely growing up among the imaginary automobiles and dead souls of Tarrytown to create out of his own imagination the beauty of his wild forebears--a mythology he cannot inherit.
Will he later hallucinate his gods? Waking among mysteries with an insane gleam of recollection?
The recognition-something so rare in his soul, met only in dreams --nostalgias of another life.
A question of the soul.
And the injured losing their injury in their innocence --a cock, a cross, an excellence of love.
And the father grieves in flophouse complexities of memory a thousand miles away, unknowing of the unexpected youthful stranger bumming toward his door.
IWhom bomb?We bomb them!Whom bomb?We bomb them!Whom bomb?We bomb them!Whom bomb?We bomb them!Whom bomb?You bomb you!Whom bomb?You bomb you!Whom bomb?You bomb you!Whom bomb?You bomb you!What do we do?Who do we bomb?What do we do?Who do we bomb?What do we do?Who do we bomb?What do we do?Who do we bomb?What do we do?You bomb! You bomb them!What do we do?You bomb! You bomb them!What do we do?We bomb! We bomb them!What do we do?We bomb! We bomb them!Whom bomb?We bomb you!Whom bomb?We bomb you!Whom bomb?You bomb you!Whom bomb?You bomb you!May 1971IIWhy bomb?We don't want to bomb!Why bomb?We don't want to bomb!Why bomb?You don't want to bomb!Why bomb?You don't want to bomb!Who said bomb?Who said we had to bomb?Who said bomb?Who said we had to bomb?Who said bomb?Who said you had to bomb?Who said bomb?Who said you had to bomb?We don't bomb!We don't bomb!We don't bomb!We don't bomb!We don't bomb!We don't bomb!We don't bomb!We don't bomb!for Don Cherry and Elvin JonesNew York, June 16, 1984IIIArmageddon did the jobGog & Magog Gog & MagogArmageddon did the jobGog & Magog Gog & MagogGog & Magog Gog & MagogArmageddon does the jobGog & Magog Gog & MagogArmageddon does the jobArmageddon for the mobGog & Magog Gog & MagogArmageddon for the mobGog & Magog Gog & MagogGog & Magog Gog & MagogGog Magog Gog MagogGog & Magog Gog & MagogGog Magog Gog MagogGog Magog Gog MagogGog Magog Gog MagogGog Magog Gog MagogGog Magog Gog MagogGinsberg says Gog & MagogArmageddon did the job.To Struga Festival Golden Wreath Laureates& International Bards 1986Stand up against governments, against God.Stay irresponsible.Say only what we know & imagine.Absolutes are coercion.Change is absolute.Ordinary mind includes eternal perceptions.Observe what's vivid.Notice what you notice.Catch yourself thinking.Vividness is self-selecting.If we don't show anyone, we're free to write anything.Remember the future.Advise only yourself.Don't drink yourself to death.Two molecules clanking against each other requires an observer to become scientific data.The measuring instrument determines the appearance of the phenomenalworld after Einstein.The universe is subjective.Walt Whitman celebrated Person.We Are an observer, measuring instrument, eye, subject, Person.Universe is person.Inside skull vast as outside skull.Mind is outer space."Each on his bed spoke to himself alone, making no sound."First thought, best thought.Mind is shapely, Art is shapely.Maximum information, minimum number of syllables.Syntax condensed, sound is solid.Intense fragments of spoken idiom, best.Consonants around vowels make sense.Savor vowels, appreciate consonants.Subject is known by what she sees.Others can measure their vision by what we see.Candor ends paranoia.Kral MajalesJune 25, 1986I hope my good old asshole holds out60 years it's been mostly OKTho in Bolivia a fissure operationsurvived the altiplano hospital-a little blood, no polyps, occasionallya small hemorrhoidactive, eager, receptive to phalluscoke bottle, candle, carrotbanana & fingers -Now AIDS makes it shy, but stilleager to serve -out with the dumps, in with the condom'dorgasmic friend -still rubbery muscular,unashamed wide open for joyBut another 20 years who knows,old folks got troubles everywhere necks, prostates, stomachs, joints--Hope the old hole stays youngtill death, relaxIn nineteen hundred forty-nineChina was won by Mao Tse-tungChiang Kai-shek's army ran awayThey were waiting there in Thailand yesterdaySupported by the CIAPushing junk down Thailand wayFirst they stole from the Meo TribesUp in the hills they started taking bribesThen they sent their soldiers up to ShanCollecting opium to send to The ManPushing junk in Bangkok yesterdaySupported by the CIABrought their jam on mule trains downTo Chiang Rai that's a railroad townSold it next to the police chief brainHe took it to town on the choochoo trainTrafficking dope to Bangkok all daySupported by the CIAThe policeman's name was Mr. PhaoHe peddled dope grand scale and howChief of border customs paidBy Central Intelligence's U.S. A.I.D.The whole operation, Newspapers saySupported by the CIAHe got so sloppy & peddled so looseHe busted himself & cooked his own gooseTook the reward for an opium loadSeizing his own haul which same he resoldBig time pusher for a decade turned greyWorking for the CIATouby Lyfong he worked for the FrenchA big fat man liked to dine & wenchPrince of the Meos he grew black mudTill opium flowed through the land like a floodCommunists came and chased the French awaySo Touby took a job with the CIAThe whole operation fell in to chaosTill U.S. Intelligence came into LaosI'll tell you no lie I'm a true AmericanOur big pusher there was Phoumi NosovanAll them Princes in a power playBut Phoumi was the man for the CIAAnd his best friend General Vang PaoRan the Meo army like a sacred cowHelicopter smugglers filled Long Cheng's barsIn Xieng Quang province on the Plain of JarsIt started in secret they were fighting yesterdayClandestine secret army of the CIAAll through the Sixties the Dope flew freeThru Tan Son Nhut Saigon to Marshal KyAir America followed throughTransporting confiture for President ThieuAll these Dealers were decades and yesterdayThe Indochinese mob of the U.S. CIAOperation Haylift Offisir Wm. ColbySaw Marshal Ky fly opium Mr. Mustard told meIndochina desk he was Chief of Dirty Tricks"Hitchhiking" with dope pushers was how he got his fixSubsidizing traffickers to drive the Reds awayTill Colby was the head of the CIAIIn the depths of the Greyhound Terminal sitting dumbly on a baggage truck looking at the sky waiting for the Los Angeles Express to depart worrying about eternity over the Post Office roof in the night-time red downtown heaven staring through my eyeglasses I realized shuddering these thoughts were not eternity, nor the poverty of our lives, irritable baggage clerks, nor the millions of weeping relatives surrounding the buses waving goodbye, nor other millions of the poor rushing around from city to city to see their loved ones, nor an indian dead with fright talking to a huge cop by the Coke machine, nor this trembling old lady with a cane taking the last trip of her life, nor the red-capped cynical porter collecting his quarters and smiling over the smashed baggage, nor me looking around at the horrible dream, nor mustached negro Operating Clerk named Spade, dealing out with his marvelous long hand the fate of thousands of express packages, nor fairy Sam in the basement limping from leaden trunk to trunk, nor Joe at the counter with his nervous breakdown smiling cowardly at the customers, nor the grayish-green whale's stomach interior loft where we keep the baggage in hideous racks, hundreds of suitcases full of tragedy rocking back and forth waiting to be opened, nor the baggage that's lost, nor damaged handles, nameplates vanished, busted wires & broken ropes, whole trunks exploding on the concrete floor, nor seabags emptied into the night in the final warehouse.
IIYet Spade reminded me of Angel, unloading a bus, dressed in blue overalls black face official Angel's workman cap, pushing with his belly a huge tin horse piled high with black baggage, looking up as he passed the yellow light bulb of the loft and holding high on his arm an iron shepherd's crook.
IIIIt was the racks, I realized, sitting myself on top of them now as is my wont at lunchtime to rest my tired foot, it was the racks, great wooden shelves and stanchions posts and beams assembled floor to roof jumbled with baggage, --the Japanese white metal postwar trunk gaudily flowered & headed for Fort Bragg, one Mexican green paper package in purple rope adorned with names for Nogales, hundreds of radiators all at once for Eureka, crates of Hawaiian underwear, rolls of posters scattered over the Peninsula, nuts to Sacramento, one human eye for Napa, an aluminum box of human blood for Stockton and a little red package of teeth for Calistogait was the racks and these on the racks I saw naked in electric light the night before I quit, the racks were created to hang our possessions, to keep us together, a temporary shift in space, God's only way of building the rickety structure of Time, to hold the bags to send on the roads, to carry our luggage from place to place looking for a bus to ride us back home to Eternity where the heart was left and farewell tears began.
IVA swarm of baggage sitting by the counter as the transcontinental bus pulls in.
The clock registering 12:15 A.M., May 9, 1956, the second hand moving forward, red.
Getting ready to load my last bus.-Farewell, Walnut Creek Richmond Vallejo Portland Pacific Highway Fleet-footed Quicksilver, God of transience.
One last package sits lone at midnight sticking up out of the Coast rack high as the dusty fluorescent light.
The wage they pay us is too low to live on. Tragedy reduced to numbers.
This for the poor shepherds. I am a communist.
Farewell ye Greyhound where I suffered so much, hurt my knee and scraped my hand and built my pectoral muscles big as a vagina.Now I'll record my secret vision, impossible sight of the face of God:It was no dream, I lay broad waking on a fabulous couch in Harlemhaving masturbated for no love, and read half naked an open book of Blakeon my lapLo & behold! I was thoughtless and turned a page and gazed on the livingSun-flowerand heard a voice, it was Blake's, reciting in earthen measure:the voice rose out of the page to my secret ear never heard before-I lifted my eyes to the window, red walls of buildings flashed outside,endless sky sad Eternitysunlight gazing on the world, apartments of Harlem standing in the universe--each brick and cornice stained with intelligence like a vast living face--the great brain unfolding and brooding in wilderness!--Now speaking aloud with Blake's voice--Love! thou patient presence & bone of the body! Father! thy careful watching and waiting over my soul!My son! My son! the endless ages have remembered me! My son! My son!Time howled in anguish in my ear!My son! My son! my father wept and held me in his dead arms.Under silver wingSan Francisco's towers sproutingthru thin gas clouds,Tamalpais black-breasted above Pacific azureBerkeley hills pine-covered below--Dr Leary in his brown house scribing IndependenceDeclarationtypewriter at windowsilver panorama in natural eyeball--Sacramento valley rivercourse's Chinese dragonflames licking green flats north-hazedState Capitol metallic rubble, dry checkered fieldsto Sierras- past Reno, Pyramid Lake's blue Altar, pure water in Nevada sands'      brown wasteland scratched by tiresJerry Rubin arrested!  Beaten, jailed,coccyx broken--Leary out of action--"a public menace...persons of tender years...immaturejudgement...pyschiatric examination..."i.e. Shut up or Else   Loonybin or SlamLeroi on bum gun rap, $7,000lawyer fees, years' negotiations--SPOCK GUILTY headlined temporary, Joan Baez'paramour husband Dave Harris to GaolDylan silent on politics, & safe--having a baby, a man--Cleaver shot at, jail'd, maddened, parole revoked,Vietnam War flesh-heap grows higher,blood splashing down the mountains of bodieson to Cholon's sidewalks--Blond boys in airplane seats fed technicolorMurderers advance w/ Death-chordsEarplugs in, steak on plasticserved--Eyes up to the Image--What do I have to lose if America falls?my body? my neck? my personality?To Ezra PoundThese are the names of the companies that have mademoney from this warnineteenhundredsixtyeight  Annodomini  fourthousandeighty HebraicThese are the Corporations who have profited by merchan-dising skinburning phosphorous or shells fragmentedto thousands of fleshpiercing needlesand here listed money millions gained by each combine formanufactureand here are gains numbered, index'd swelling a decade, setin order,here named the Fathers in office in these industries, tele-phones directing finance,names of directors, makers of fates, and the names of the stockholders of these destined Aggregates,and here are the names of their ambassadors to the Capital,representatives to legislature, those who sit drinkingin hotel lobbies to persuade,and separate listed, those who drop Amphetamine withmilitary, gossip, argue, and persuadesuggesting policy naming language proposing strategy, thisdone for fee as ambassadors to Pentagon, consul-tants to military, paid by their industry:and these are the names of the generals & captains mili-tary, who know thus work for war goods manufactur-ers;and above these, listed, the names of the banks, combines,investment trusts that control these industries:and these are the names of the newspapers owned by thesebanksand these are the names of the airstations owned by thesecombines;and these are the numbers of thousands of citizens em-ployed by these businesses named;and the beginning of this accounting is 1958 and the end1968, that static be contained in orderly mind,coherent and definite,and the first form of this litany begun first day December1967 furthers this poem of these States.That tree saidI don't like that white car under me,it smells gasolineThat other tree next to it saidO you're always complainingyou're a neuroticyou can see by the way you're bent over.I -- A Pleasant Afternoonfor Michael Brownstein and Dick GallupOne day 3 poets and 60 ears sat under a green-striped Chau-tauqua tent in Auroralistening to Black spirituals, tapping their feet, appreciatingwords singing by in mountain windson a pleasant sunny day of rest -- the wild wind blew thrublue Heavensfilled with fluffy clouds stretched from Central City to RockyFlats, Plutonium sizzled in its secret bed,hot dogs sizzled in the Lion's Club lunchwagon microwavemouth, orangeade bubbled over in waxen cupsTraffic moved along Colefax, meditators silent in the DiamondCastle shrine-room at Boulder followed the breath goingout of their nostrils,Nobody could remember anything, spirits flew out of mouths& noses, out of the sky, across Colorado plains & thetent flapped happily open spacious & didn't fall down.June 18, 1978II -- Peace ProtestCumulus clouds float across blue skyover the white-walled Rockwell Corporation factory-- am I going to stop that?*Rocky Mountains rising behind usDenver shining in morning light-- Led away from the crowd by police and photographers*Middleaged Ginsberg and Ellsberg taken down the roadto the greyhaired Sheriff's van -But what about Einstein? What about Einstein? Hey, EinsteinCome back!III -- Golden CourthouseWaiting for the Judge, breathing silentPrisoners, witnesses, Police -the stenographer yawns into her palms.August 9, 1978IV -- Everybody's FantasyI walked outside & the bomb'ddropped lots of plutoniumall over the Lower East SideThere weren't any buildings left justiron skeletonsgroceries burned, potholes open to stinking sewer watersThere were people starving and crawlingacross the desertthe Martian UFOs with blueLight destroyer rayspassed over and dried up all the watersCharred Amazon palmtrees forhundreds of miles on both sidesof the riverAugust 10, 1978V -- Waiting Room at the Rocky Flats Plutonium Plant"Give us the weapons we need to protect ourselves!"the bareheaded guard lifts his flyswatter above the desk-- whap!*A green-letter'd shield on the pressboard wall!"Life is fragile.  Handle with care" --My Goodness! here's where they make the nuclear bombtriggers.August 17, 1978VI -- Numbers in Red Notebook2,000,000 killed in Vietnam13,000,000 refugees in Indochina 1972200,000,000 years for the Galaxy to revolve on its core24,000 the Babylonian Great Year24,000 half life of plutonium2,000 the most I ever got for a poetry reading80,000 dolphins killed in the dragnet4,000,000,000 years earth been bornIWhat new element before us unborn in nature? Is therea new thing under the Sun?At last inquisitive Whitman a modern epic, detonative,Scientific themeFirst penned unmindful by Doctor Seaborg with poison-ous hand, named for Death's planet through the sea beyond Uranuswhose chthonic ore fathers this magma-teared Lord of Hades, Sire of avenging Furies, billionaire Hell-King worshipped oncewith black sheep throats cut, priests's face averted fromunderground mysteries in single temple at Eleusis,Spring-green Persephone nuptialed to his inevitableShade, Demeter mother of asphodel weeping dew,her daughter stored in salty caverns under white snow, black hail, grey winter rain or Polar ice, immemor-able seasons beforeFish flew in Heaven, before a Ram died by the starrybush, before the Bull stamped sky and earthor Twins inscribed their memories in clay or Crab'dfloodwashed memory from the skull, or Lion sniffed thelilac breeze in Eden--Before the Great Year began turning its twelve signs,ere constellations wheeled for twenty-four thousandsunny yearsslowly round their axis in Sagittarius, one hundred sixty-seven thousand times returning to this nightRadioactive Nemesis were you there at the beginning black dumb tongueless unsmelling blast of Disil-lusion?I manifest your Baptismal Word after four billion yearsI guess your birthday in Earthling Night, I salute yourdreadful presence last majestic as the Gods,Sabaot, Jehova, Astapheus, Adonaeus, Elohim, Iao, Ialdabaoth, Aeon from Aeon born ignorant in anAbyss of Light,Sophia's reflections glittering thoughtful galaxies, whirl-pools of starspume silver-thin as hairs of Einstein!Father Whitman I celebrate a matter that renders Selfoblivion!Grand Subject that annihilates inky hands & pages'prayers, old orators' inspired Immortalities,I begin your chant, openmouthed exhaling into spacioussky over silent mills at Hanford, Savannah River,Rocky Flats, Pantex, Burlington, AlbuquerqueI yell thru Washington, South Carolina, Colorado, Texas, Iowa, New Mexico,Where nuclear reactors creat a new Thing under the Sun, where Rockwell war-plants fabricate this deathstuff trigger in nitrogen baths,Hanger-Silas Mason assembles the terrified weaponsecret by ten thousands, & where Manzano Moun-tain boasts to storeits dreadful decay through two hundred forty milleniawhile our Galaxy spirals around its nebulous core.I enter your secret places with my mind, I speak with your presence, I roar your Lion Roar with mortalmouth.One microgram inspired to one lung, ten pounds of heavy metal dust adrift slow motion over greyAlpsthe breadth of the planet, how long before your radiancespeeds blight and death to sentient beings?Enter my body or not I carol my spirit inside you,Unnaproachable Weight,O heavy heavy Element awakened I vocalize your con-sciousness to six worldsI chant your absolute Vanity.  Yeah monster of Angerbirthed in fear O mostIgnorant matter ever created unnatural to Earth! Delusionof metal empires!Destroyer of lying Scientists! Devourer of covetousGenerals, Incinerator of Armies & Melter of Wars!Judgement of judgements, Divine Wind over vengeful nations, Molester of Presidents, Death-Scandal ofCapital politics! Ah civilizations stupidly indus-trious!Canker-Hex on multitudes learned or illiterate! Manu-factured Spectre of human reason! O solidifiedimago of practicioner in Black ArtsI dare your reality, I challenge your very being! I publish your cause and effect!I turn the wheel of Mind on your three hundred tons!Your name enters mankind's ear! I embody yourultimate powers!My oratory advances on your vaunted Mystery! This breath dispels your braggart fears! I sing your form at lastbehind your concrete & iron walls inside your fortressof rubber & translucent silicon shields in filteredcabinets and baths of lathe oil,My voice resounds through robot glove boxes & ignot cans and echoes in electric vaults inert of atmo-sphere,I enter with spirit out loud into your fuel rod drumsunderground on soundless thrones and beds ofleadO density! This weightless anthem trumpets transcendent through hidden chambers and breaks through iron doors into the Infernal Room!Over your dreadful vibration this measured harmony        floats audible, these jubilant tones are honey and milk and wine-sweet waterPoured on the stone black floor, these syllables arebarley groats I scatter on the Reactor's core, I call your name with hollow vowels, I psalm your Fateclose by, my breath near deathless ever at yoursideto Spell your destiny, I set this verse prophetic on yourmausoleum walls to seal you up Eternally withDiamond Truth!  O doomed Plutonium.IIThe Bar surveys Plutonian history from midnight lit with Mercury Vapor streetlamps till in dawn's early lighthe contemplates a tranquil politic spaced out between Nations' thought-forms proliferating bureaucratic& horrific arm'd, Satanic industries projected suddenwith Five Hundred Billion Dollar Strengtharound the world same time this text is set in Boulder,Colorado before front range of Rocky Mountainstwelve miles north of Rocky Flats Nuclear Facility in United States of North America, Western Hemi-sphereof planet Earth six months and fourteen days aroundour Solar System in a Spiral Galaxythe local year after Dominion of the last God nineteen hundred seventy eightCompleted as yellow hazed dawn clouds brighten East,Denver city white belowBlue sky transparent rising empty deep & spacious to a morning star high over the balcony above some autos sat with wheels to curb downhill from Flatiron's jagged pine ridge,sunlit mountain meadows sloped to rust-red sandstonecliffs above brick townhouse roofsas sparrows waked whistling through Marine Street'ssummer green leafed trees.IIIThis ode to you O Poets and Orators to come, youfather Whitman as I join your side, you Congressand American people,you present meditators, spiritual friends & teachers,you O Master of the Diamond Arts,Take this wheel of syllables in hand, these vowels and consonants to breath's endtake this inhalation of black poison to your heart, breathout this blessing from your breast on our creation forests cities oceans deserts rocky flats and mountains in the Ten Directions pacify with exhalation,enrich this Plutonian Ode to explode its empty thunderthrough earthen thought-worldsMagnetize this howl with heartless compassion, destroythis mountain of Plutonium with ordinary mindand body speech,thus empower this Mind-guard spirit gone out, goneout, gone beyond, gone beyond me, Wake space,so Ah!The flower in the glass peanut bottle formerly in thekitchen crooked to take a place in the light, the closet door opened, because I used it before, itkindly stayed open waiting for me, its owner.I began to feel my misery in pallet on floor, listeningto music, my misery, that's why I want to sing.The room closed down on me, I expected the presence of the Creator, I saw my gray painted walls andceiling, they contained my room, they containedmeas the sky contained my garden,I opened my doorThe rambler vine climbed up the cottage post,the leaves in the night still where the day had placedthem, the animal heads of the flowers where they had arisento think at the sunCan I bring back the words? Will thought of transcription haze my mental open eye?The kindly search for growth, the gracious de-sire to exist of the flowers, my near ecstasy at existingamong themThe privilege to witness my existence-you toomust seek the sun...My books piled up before me for my usewaiting in space where I placed them, theyhaven't disappeared, time's left its remnants and qual-ities for me to use--my words piled up, my texts, my manuscripts, my loves.I had a moment of clarity, saw the feeling inthe heart of things, walked out to the garden crying.Saw the red blossoms in the night light, sun's gone, they had all grown, in a moment, and were wait-ing stopped in time for the day sun to come and givethem...Flowers which as in a dream at sunset I wateredfaithfully not knowing how much I loved them.I am so lonely in my glory--except they too outthere--I looked up--those red bush blossoms beckon-ing and peering in the window waiting in the blind love,their leaves too have hope and are upturned top flatto the sky to receive--all creation open to receive--the flat earth itself.The music descends, as does the tall bending stalk of the heavy blssom, because it has to, to stayalive, to continue to the last drop of joy.The world knows the love that's in its breast asin the flower, the suffering lonely world.The Father is merciful.The light socket is crudely attached to the ceil-ing, after the house was built, to receive a plug whichsticks in it alright, and serves my phonograph now...The closet door is open for me, where I left it,since I left it open, it has graciously stayed open.The kitchen has no door, the hole there will admit me should I wish to enter the kitchen.I remember when I first got laid, H.P. gra-ciously took my cherry, I sat on the docks of Prov-incetown, age 23, joyful, elevated in hope with theFather, the door to the womb wasopen to admit meif I wished to enter.There are unused electricity plugs all over myhouse if I ever needed them.The kitchen window is open, to admit air...The telephone--sad to relate--sits on thefloor--I haven't had the money to get it connected--I want people to bow when they see me and sayhe is gifted with poetry, he has seen the presence ofthe CreatorAnd the Creator gave me a shot of his presenceto gratify my wish, so as not to cheat me of my yearningfor him.O dear sweet rosy unattainable desire ...how sad, no way to change the mad cultivated asphodel, the visible reality...
and skin's appalling petals--how inspired to be so Iying in the living room drunk naked and dreaming, in the absence of electricity...
over and over eating the low root of the asphodel, gray fate...
rolling in generation on the flowery couch as on a bank in Arden-my only rose tonite's the treat of my own nudity.
Tail turned to red sunset on a juniper crown a lone magpie cawks.Mad at Oryoki in the shrine-room -- Thistles blossomed late afternoon.Put on my shirt and took it off in the sun walking the path to lunch.A dandelion seed floats above the marsh grass with the mosquitos.At 4 A.M. the two middleaged men sleeping together holding hands.In the half-light of dawn a few birds warble under the Pleiades.Sky reddens behind fir trees, larks twitter, sparrows cheep cheep cheepcheep cheep.July 1983Caught shoplifting ran out the department store at sunrise and woke up.Pigeons shake their wings on the copper church roofout my window across the street, a bird perched on the crosssurveys the city's blue-grey clouds. Larry Rivers'll come at 10 AM and take my picture. I'm takingyour picture, pigeons.  I'm writing you down, Dawn.I'm immortalizing your exhaust, Avenue A bus.O Thought! Now you'll have to think the same thing forever!